Drawn by a landscape as white as snow,
Masshiro na keshiki ni ima sasowarete
I'm headed toward an unseen world.
Boku wa yuku yo mada minu sekai e
I've been traveling while lost
Maigo no mama tabi shiteita
Under this gray sky.
Nezumiiro no sora no shita
Every day with new maps, stained with my many dreams.
Higawari no chizu ikutsumo no yume ga nijindeita
I wonder if someday,
Itsuka wa sa
Even with these tiny steps of mine,
Chippoke na boku no kono hohaba demo
I'll be able to travel beyond those clouds.
Ano kumo no mukou made yukeru kana
I put on a bold front.
Tsuyogatte
End up hurting myself.
Kizutsuita
I feel empty inside.
Kokoro sukashita youni
It's started to rain,
Furidashita
And the raindrops
Amatsubu tachi ga
Began to repeat their scattered reflections.
Ranhansha kurikaesu
These straight rays of light
Massugu na hikari ga
Start to cross one another.
Kousa shite
And without telling anyone where they're headed,
Yakusaki mo tsugenumama
Across the endless distances,
Doko made mo
They pass through all matter.
Tsukinukeru
I burn these faint afterimages onto my eyes.
Awai zanzou ryoume ni yakitsukete
Under this sky,
Kono sora no shita
Wherever I am,
Donna toko ni itemo
I should be able to reach
Todoku hazu nanda
The unseen world.
Mada minu sekai e
That was so exhausting!
They were watching us the whole time, too.
Mr. Fu and Ran Fan, right?
Hey!
Where's the young master!?
I don't see him...
Could he have gone missing again?
Seriously... The instant I take my eyes off him...
Young master!
Where have you gone?!
I hope he hasn't collapsed somewhere like last time...
Good riddance.
Let's go.
Okay...
Young master! Where are you?!
There's something... odd about this country.
Footsteps of a
Comrade-in-Arms
It's me. I came to visit.
Good work.
From the Colonel.
Yo, it's the cigarette kid!
How are you doing? Were you even able to beat him once?
Not a chance.
This game is pretty boring, too.
Hey, I can go cut people up if it's just at night, right?
Of course not!
Then, could you at least... bring that Hawkeye lady?
Yeah, I'll mention it to her.
How much longer do I have to watch over this guy?
What did the Colonel say?
"Sorry for putting you in charge of such a dangerous task."
"Don't worry about military duty, though."
"I've marked you down as absent due to illness."
"However, you're as good as dead if a civilian
or someone from the military besides us finds you."
...is what he said.
Any good news?
Yup.
Huh? What is it?
I got a girlfriend!
She really helped me out when I was struggling with the transfer and all.
She's such a babe, too!
Hey, do you think I'd enjoy cutting her up?
Just go home already...
Oh my.
What's wrong with him?
Hey, are you all right?
Is he okay?
F-Food...
He's completely out of it.
Where's he from?
What? You came from Xing?
That's so far...
By the way, where's your certificate of entry?
Make way! Make way!
Illegal entrant coming through!
Young master! Where are you?!
He's passed out somewhere... I just know he has!
Well, let's go say hi to the military first.
Let's.
Then... I think I'll go visit Mr. Hughes' place first.
I can't wait to see Miss Gracia and Elicia, either.
Okay.
We'll head over there afterwards.
Well, see you then.
I wonder if Lt. Colonel Hughes uncovered
more information about the stone for us since then.
Well, the Führer President warned him to stay out of it, too.
Let's give him the information we obtained, first.
Homunculus...
Yeah.
The Lt. Colonel should be at the military chambers...
Over there!
Sheska?
Sheska!
Yes?
You have the key to that room, right?
Yes, I do.
Oh... Room 3, you mean?
I've kind of made a mess in there...
Don't worry about it. I just need to grab some documents.
I'm telling you, it's not all right.
I'll clean it up right away, so please give me a moment!
Okay. I'll come get it later, so please finish by then.
Y-Yes, ma'am!
Umm... Colonel?
Colonel Mustang.
How many minutes was I asleep?
I'd say about ten.
I don't have much time before the army council.
Excuse my unsolicited advice, but perhaps
you should rest instead of straining yourself?
Yeah, I'll come again.
Was that Colonel Mustang?
G-Good morning, Captain Focker!
Morning, Sheska.
But why was the Colonel here?
W-Well... you see...
The door to the archives is open, too.
I'm sorry! The truth is, well...
Let me guess, the colonel railroaded through, right?
I'll keep it a secret.
Thank you so much!
But I wonder what he was looking up?
Any idea?
I don't know the details either,
but he asked me whether there were
any documents concerning Research Laboratory 5.
That, and the murder of Brigadier General Hughes...
It's thanks to the Brigadier General that I got a job here.
Ah, that's right.
Well, there's a lot of work to do today as always.
I'm counting on you.
Yes, sir.
Morning, Sheska.
Yes? Huh?
What?
Hello.
Did you perhaps lose some weight?
I might have.
You were injured?
Just some trouble down south.
It's just a scratch.
I see.
By the way, I met the Elric Brothers while I was down there.
A coincidence. They were meeting their master, who lives in Dublith.
Major.
Yes?
Have you told them about Hughes' death?
No, I couldn't bring myself to tell them.
They'll find out sooner or later.
I know that, sir.
Research Laboratory 5 and the philosopher's stones.
The ingredients to the stones are live humans.
He was such an accommodating guy.
He probably stuck his nose into what the Elric Brothers were researching and uncovered something he shouldn't have.
Is that why you won't tell them?
If they find out Hughes died because he got involved with them, they'd be devastated...
You're too kind.
And you know too much.
I'm almost there.
Please be careful.
No one knows who could be listening.
I'll be going on ahead.
Huh? Lieutenant Hawkeye!
Ah, it's been a while.
If you're here, that means...
Sorry to make you wait.
I knew it...
Oh, Fullmetal.
Why the hell are you here, Colonel?
I was transferred to Central effective last month.
And what about you? What brings you here?
Just collecting some information.
We were also thinking about going to say hi to Lt. Colonel Hughes.
How's he doing?
He's no longer here.
Huh?
He decided to retire to the country.
He's going to take over the family business along with his wife and daughter.
So he's not here.
Oh... that's too bad.
We were looking forward to seeing him, too...
Fullmetal.
Don't jump the gun and do anything reckless.
Sure.
Treating them like children only at a time like this?
They don't need to know right now.
It's better if there are fewer obstacles for those brothers to move forward.
But they'll find out eventually.
I don't have the right to call
Major Armstrong soft-hearted, either.
Soft-hearted?
Don't you mean cruel?
So the Lt. Colonel isn't around, huh...
Oh, I almost forgot, Brother.
We have to let Winry know.
She's headed for his home.
You're right.
Second Lieutenant Ross!
It's been a while, you two.
What's the hurry?
We heard about Lt. Colonel Hughes, so...
I see...
It's hard, isn't it?
There was so much I wanted to say to him, too...
I wish we had a chance to have a proper farewell with him.
No one contacted you about it, huh?
Don't worry.
The army gave him a proper farewell.
Really? That's nice of you guys.
Of course.
Also, you may have heard this already, but he was specially promoted two ranks to the rank of Brigadier General.
Specially promoted two ranks?
He was specially promoted for retiring to the country?
Second Lieutenant Ross!
Here you go.
Thanks.
You can't be serious! Why was he...
Why?!
Brother!
Brigadier General Hughes was murdered by someone soon after you were released from the hospital.
They haven't caught the perpetrator yet.
It's my fault...
I dragged him into this! Lt. Colonel Hughes!
Well, careful out there.
Be sure to drop by if you ever come to Central again.
Oh, Alphonse, you can't eat with that armor on, can you?
You guys probably haven't booked a place to stay at yet, right?
If so, stay at my place.
Papa!
What are you going to do?
I'm going to tell them everything.
You head back.
I'm the only one who needs to face them.
It's not just your problem.
It concerns both of us.
So I'm going, too.
Hey, Al.
What if-
We chose to get our bodies back no matter what,
but if people end up dying because of it, I'd rather not.
Winry just came by, too...
We know.
Winry.
There's something I need to tell you, Miss Gracia.
Is that okay?
Something to tell me?
Yes.
And to Winry, too.
So my husband uncovered something about these philosopher's stones...
And his death is the murderers' way of saying "don't meddle in our affairs"?
We basically dragged him in.
I'm so sorry.
I'm terribly sorry...
If he died while trying to help someone, then that's just like him.
He's always been a meddling, accommodating kind of guy, and he'd always end up losing things due to his kindness.
But I don't think he's ever regretted it.
Even till the moment of his death.
We're...
Don't tell me you're going to give up.
If you two give up here, it'd mean
my husband's death was completely meaningless.
Even if it's impossible with the philosopher's stones, there may be other ways, right?
Miss Gracia...
Move forward on the path you're content with.
Mama...
Please don't cry, Mama...
You're in there, right, Winry?
You haven't eaten yet, have you?
The dining hall's going to close soon.
Okay...
You won't be able to function without food.
Yeah...
Well, I'm heading back to my room.
Apple pie?
I practiced making it a few times since then.
I don't mean to brag, but I've gotten really good at it.
Well, it's nowhere near as good as Miss Gracia's, though...
Someday...
I wanted Mr. Hughes to try it.
The Colonel is digging around
for information about Hughes' death?
Yeah.
I wonder if he's discovered anything?
Maybe.
What do we do?
We moved him to Central to keep an eye on him...
Can't he just behave?
He's a precious candidate for sacrifice.
You haven't gotten any information out of your boyfriend?
Nothing.
I can't even tell if he's foolish or able.
I'll go hunt for some information again.
We're going, Gluttony.
Geez, Gluttony! Don't leave this place a mess!
Seriously...
Hey, Lust?
We just need the Flame Alchemist to behave, right?
That's right.
Are you up for taking another measure?
Got something on your mind?
The best way to shut up an annoying dog is to give him some food.
Second Lieutenant Maria Ross.
I'm Henry Douglas from military police headquarters.
Can I help you?
You're coming with me.
Your sidearm.
Care to explain?
Your name has been called as a
material witness in the murder of Maes Hughes.
That's impossible!
You can explain yourself later.
Come with me.
Second Lieutenant Maria Ross is denying all charges.
Collect all data concerning her.
Make it quick.
However, do it in strict secrecy.
Yes, sir!
Hey lady, could you wrap up these flowers for me?
Oh my, are you going on a date? You lady-killer!
Did I make you wait, Solaris?
No, I just got here.
I've been dying to see you, Jean.
I'm looking forward to hearing your interesting stories again.
I don't have to act tough, right?
Tsuyogaranakute iindane
The scribbling someone made...
Dareka ga kaitetta
On the wall, of a flower is swaying.
Kabe no rakugaki no hana ga yureru
No one knows their true selves.
Jibunrashisa nante dermo wakaranaiyo
Even though we both lose and gain
Nagai nagai michi no tochuu de
By embarking on this long, long path,
Nakushitari hirottari
And though there may be days loneliness strikes and makes us weep...
Kyuu ni samishikunatte naichau hi mo arukedo
Let's transform our tears and pains to stars.
Namida mo itami mo hoshi ni kaeyou
Let's light a candle to illuminate our tomorrow.
Ashita wo terasu akari wo tomosou
And we'll hold our small hands over the fire to create stardust,
Chiisana te kazashite futari de tsukurou
And an eternity that shines so brilliantly.
Hoshikuzu wo tsuyoku hikaru eien wo
Farewells may be unavoidable,
Sayonara itsuka wa kurukamoshirenai
Yet the seasons continue to change obliviously.
Kisetsu wa soredemo meguri megutteku
Even if I lose myself, I'll continue to walk...
Chiisaku mayottemo aruiteku
Walk by your side.
Kimi to aruiteku
That's the only thing I'd like to never change.
Sore dake wa kawaranaideiyoune
The sacrificial lamb is engulfed in the flames of hatred...
...and leaves the boy with feelings of hate and regret.
And the man reaches out to the darkness.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Cold Flame
Episode 17, Cold Flame.
All is playing into the hands of the unknown.